Guide to the Frederick O. Glover Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frederic O. Glover papers
1949-1979
SC0234
Glover, Frederic O.
1 Linear feet
These papers were created by Glover while he worked in the President's Office under Stanford University Presidents J.E. Wallace Sterling, Kenneth Pitzer, and Richard W. Lyman. Included are incoming and outgoing correspondence, files pertaining to Ad Hoc Trustees Budget Committees, newspaper clippings, and subject files.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Frederic O. Glover enjoyed a long association with Stanford University. A member of the class of 1933, Glover returned to Stanford in 1946 as its first full-time director of information. In 1952 he moved to the President's office as assistant to President J.E. Wallace Sterling and was promoted in 1959 to executive assistant. He remained in the President's office under President Kenneth Pitzer, 1968-70, and then was appointed secretary to the university by President Richard W. Lyman. Glover retired in 1977 but remained active at Stanford as a founding member of the Stanford Historical Society and a member of the Stanford Associates. He also started the Stanford Oral History Project, a joint effort of the Stanford Historical Society and the Stanford University Archives. Fred Glover died of cancer on November 18, 1993.
Scope and Contents
These papers were created by Glover while he worked in the President's Office under Stanford University Presidents J.E. Wallace Sterling, Kenneth Pitzer, and Richard W. Lyman. Included are incoming and outgoing correspondence, files pertaining to Ad Hoc Trustees Budget Committees, newspaper clippings, and subject files.
Access Terms
Lyman, Richard W.; Pitzer, Kenneth; Stanford University--Administration.; Stanford University--Presidents.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1955, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1960, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Incoming, Outgoing, 1964, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: Outgoing, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- List of Lyman's Announcement as President, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence and a script honoring Pitzer, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- SRI - Problems (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Inaugaration Sterling (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling to Frederic O. Glover, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, J.E. Wallace Sterling, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Ad Hoc Trustees Budget Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ad Hoc Trustees Budget Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ad Hoc Trustees Budget Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Vucinich (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Winbigler (Box 2, Folder 5)
- News clippings, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Confidential (Box 2, Folder 7)